<revision>
<id>882008113</id>
<parentid>881974330</parentid>
<timestamp>2019-02-06T06:23:48Z</timestamp>
<contributor>
<username>RogerGLewis</username>
<id>9330272</id>
</contributor>
<origin>882008113</origin>
<model>wikitext</model>
<format>text/x-wiki</format>
<text bytes="3129" sha1="5rc5lyoa3zqns38aalpoxr3rhhihuzj" xml:space="preserve">== History ==

100 people and top academics around the world signing letters did not come out of no-where. XR can be traced back to https://web.archive.org/web/20151015172755/https://compassionate-revolution.net/ and this Compassionate Revolution Ltd. is a company that then has Rising Up! and Extinction Rebellion derived from it. Wayback machine has it appearing in 2015. The campaign of Extinction Rebellion began in the planning in 2018, in the Spring. BUT even looking in 2015 there were people thinking about ecological politics involved from the start. Many of the figures involved were activists long before Occupy emerged around 2011. IN fact some can trace their direct action to the Reclaim the Streets! of the 1990s. How tenuous this chain is or how much this influenced the modern XR is not easy to say. There are probably not sources that say this to wikipedia standards. Rather looking at the key individuals and their histories would be a better way of assessing this. However a lot were not activists and not involved in any groups or gatherings.  &lt;!-- Template:Unsigned IP --&gt;&lt;small class="autosigned"&gt;—&amp;nbsp;Preceding [[Wikipedia:Signatures|unsigned]] comment added by [[Special:Contributions/84.249.7.24|84.249.7.24]] ([[User talk:84.249.7.24#top|talk]]) 18:24, 11 January 2019 (UTC)&lt;/small&gt; &lt;!--Autosigned by SineBot--&gt;

:: There are two key articles related to this Activism initiative &lt;ref&gt;http://www.wrongkindofgreen.org/2019/01/28/the-manufacturing-of-greta-thunberg-for-consent-the-most-inconvenient-truth-capitalism-is-in-danger-of-falling-apart/&lt;/ref&gt; and this response from Greta Thunberg &lt;ref&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greta_Thunberg &lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt; https://www.ecowatch.com/greta-thunberg-climate-strike-2627956100.html&lt;/ref&gt; aspects of manufacturing consent and controlled opposition and Gatekeepers all figure and the initiative should not be left here un-critically, the pedagogical aspects of Wikipedia should not be ignored to promote activism.&lt;ref&gt;https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/02/05/greenkeepers-gophers-usefullidiots-and-donteatyellowsnow/&lt;/ref&gt; I will work up a påaragraph with the first two references as this article is really a trotting out of the PR campaign from &lt;ref&gt;https://wedonthavetime.org/launch/&lt;/ref&gt; [[User:RogerGLewis|RogerGLewis]] ([[User talk:RogerGLewis|talk]]) 06:05, 6 February 2019 (UTC)
New Section Needed, Controversy! 

There are two key articles related to this Activism initiative &lt;ref&gt;http://www.wrongkindofgreen.org/2019/01/28/the-manufacturing-of-greta-thunberg-for-consent-the-most-inconvenient-truth-capitalism-is-in-danger-of-falling-apart/&lt;/ref&gt; and this response from Greta Thunberg &lt;ref&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greta_Thunberg &lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt; https://www.ecowatch.com/greta-thunberg-climate-strike-2627956100.html&lt;/ref&gt; aspects of manufacturing consent and controlled opposition and Gatekeepers all figure and the initiative should not be left here un-critically, this article is really trotting out of the PR campaign from &lt;ref&gt;https://wedonthavetime.org/launch/&lt;/ref&gt; [[User:RogerGLewis|RogerGLewis]] ([[User talk:RogerGLewis|talk]])</text>
<sha1>5rc5lyoa3zqns38aalpoxr3rhhihuzj</sha1>
</revision>