<revision>
<id>6642959</id>
<parentid>6642622</parentid>
<timestamp>2004-10-17T05:46:49Z</timestamp>
<contributor>
<username>Krupo</username>
<id>63592</id>
</contributor>
<origin>6642959</origin>
<model>wikitext</model>
<format>text/x-wiki</format>
<text bytes="3060" sha1="9ep724erxnmgn1dvglcswhnuton6h5l" xml:space="preserve">'''Naomi Klein''' (born [[1970]]) is a Canadian [[journalist]], [[author]] and [[activist]]. She was born in [[Montreal]], [[Quebec]], and now lives in [[Toronto]]. 

Klein wrote the book ''[[No Logo]]'' ([[2000]]), which became a [[manifesto]] of the [[anti-globalization movement]].  She has also written ''[[Fences and Windows]]'' ([[2002]]) and contributes to ''[[The Nation]]'', ''[[In These Times]]'', [[Canada]]'s ''[[The Globe and Mail]]'', and ''[[The Guardian]]'' in [[United Kingdom|Britain]].

Her writing career started early, contributing the Varsity, one of the [[University of Toronto]]'s student newspapers.

''No Logo'' was one of the first publications to receive feedback from [[Nike, Inc.|Nike]], a company Klein frequently criticizes in the book. One of her most important writings is an article in Harper's Magazine September 2004, entitled "Pillaging Iraq in pursuit of a neocon utopia". In this Harper's article she argues that the Bush Administration definitely did have a clear plan for post-invasion Iraq, which was to build a fully unconstrained free market economy.  Under Paul Bremer's orders, foreigners became able to own 100% of Iraqi assets, pay no corporate taxes and take all profits out of Iraq.  She describes how Bremer's plan was to sell off Iraq's industry on forty year contracts in the short seven months between appointment of [[Iyad Allawi]] and the January 2005 elections.  The key obstacle to Bremer's plan was that it was illegal under the Hague Regulations of 1907 and the Geneva Conventions of 1947.  She argues well that it was this profit motive that was at least in part a driving force for the invasion of Iraq and destruction of the apparatus of the Iraqi state.  She suggests that the 2 March 2004 explosions of five bombs in front of the Shia mosques of Karbala and Baghdad, which killed close to 200 worshipers, was successful in getting the Shia cleric Grand Ayatollah Ali al Sistani to sign the interim constitution.  

Klein is married to Canadian television journalist [[Avi Lewis]].

{{cleanup}}

== External links ==

* [http://www.nologo.org The No Logo website]
* [http://www.jasondiceman.com/projects/no_logo_doc An Introduction to Naomi Klein's No Logo], a [[Macromedia Flash|Flash]] animated movie
* [http://www.guardian.co.uk/Columnists/Archive/0,5673,-991,0.html Archive of Naomi Klein's articles at ''The Guardian'']
* [http://www.thenation.com/directory/bios/bio.mhtml?id=337 Archive of Naomi Klein's articles at ''The Nation'']
* [http://www.harpers.org/BaghdadYearZero.html Baghdad Year Zero: Pillaging Iraq in pursuit of a neocon utopia]
* [http://www.democracynow.org/article.pl?sid=04/10/13/144220 Interview with Kaomi Klein about her article "James Baker's Double Life"]

[[Category:1970 births|Naomi Klein]]
[[Category:Canadian journalists|Klein, Naomi]]
[[Category:Canadian writers|Klein, Naomi]]
[[Category:Political writers|Klein, Naomi]]

[[de:Naomi Klein]]
[[fr:Naomi Klein]]
[[ja:%E3%83%8A%E3%82%AA%E3%83%9F%E3%83%BB%E3%82%AF%E3%83%A9%E3%82%A4%E3%83%B3]]
[[no:Naomi Klein]]</text>
<sha1>9ep724erxnmgn1dvglcswhnuton6h5l</sha1>
</revision>